<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Blog on The Real Hathai</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/categories/blog/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Blog on The Real Hathai</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hathai25.github.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Reminiscence</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/reminiscence/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/reminiscence/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/reminiscence/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Reminiscence" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A day can be special in many ways. So does the 9th of May.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started at the beginning of 2018. The year that my life completely changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four years ago, someone stepped into my life. Someone used to be dreamy and mournful at the same time. Someone added laughter and tears to my daily days, emotions, and things that you could never forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone said yes on this day. Someone received a ring on this day, even though it didn&amp;rsquo;t fit at first. Someone tore me apart on this day, right before many decisive exams - I can still remember I was crying while doing that Toeic test. Someone came back, also on this day, after leaving for half a year, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t stay till the same day four years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where did we go wrong?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not someone&amp;rsquo;s fault, it&amp;rsquo;s just life separates us into different paths. You couldn&amp;rsquo;t chase after your dream and become a person I&amp;rsquo;ve never known. I achieved more than I can ever think of and become a person I&amp;rsquo;ve never expected. We both have gone so far from our path, increasing the distance between us. Do you think so?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if those years are enough for a lifetime. It&amp;rsquo;s stupid thinking so, but when I try to be in a new relationship or intend to, I just feel like trying to repeat everything in the past. Maybe I let others down, but what can I say?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to be nostalgic or missing someone. In the end, the memories stay, they might haunt you for days and nights, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got over that time. Now I can sit back and be calmful recalling everything, with a smile and pity on my face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, what a love story that was!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever come across this, just know that I cherish all the things we&amp;rsquo;ve been through. All the good and bad memories, all took part in making me who I am today. Maybe one day when everything is long gone, we&amp;rsquo;ll meet again, but as a different, grown person, with all the memories left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whatever happened, you and I, we both deserve to be appreciated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Dawn Ahead</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Dawn Ahead" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s May. Summer is coming, with plenty of work ahead for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I have some projects to finish. One is from my club, which is to make some kinda blog website. One is from my class, in which I have to develop software to illustrate some sorting algorithms. Both are pretty challenging and even though I&amp;rsquo;ve been really familiar with such projects, they&amp;rsquo;ll still take me lots of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I&amp;rsquo;m competing in the &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative Idea Challenge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; at my university - a contest for students to present their startup ideas. If I can make it through the final round, I can present my idea in front of many people in English at the &lt;strong&gt;B1 lecture hall&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be a big day, and I really look forward to that, since that hall is incredibly cool, you can see it below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/hall.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1000&#34;
	height=&#34;667&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/hall_hu930af4a35d7dcb9c96ec2f135ef66885_324575_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/hall_hu930af4a35d7dcb9c96ec2f135ef66885_324575_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;149&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;359px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I&amp;rsquo;m having my mid-term exams at the end of the month,  just in time the above contest is over. This semester I&amp;rsquo;m studying &lt;strong&gt;13&lt;/strong&gt; subjects, which is an insane number (at least to me). But I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid. I will never give up once I&amp;rsquo;ve set the goals for myself, so let&amp;rsquo;s see how far I can go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny how terrible and stress I was last week and now I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get through everything. Today is labour day, and I think I can really sit back, chill out, enjoy the air of my countryside, as I can hardly have the chance to feel it once more the following month. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it peaceful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/sunset.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;2559&#34;
	height=&#34;2560&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/sunset_hu7a65db6189653c66a7a076cebc2d7774_887281_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://hathai25.github.io/p/dawn-ahead/sunset_hu7a65db6189653c66a7a076cebc2d7774_887281_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The title is dawn, but this picture is the sunset =))&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;99&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;239px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here.we.go!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Gloomy Sunday</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/gloomy-sunday/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/gloomy-sunday/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/gloomy-sunday/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Gloomy Sunday" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Sunday, the end of the week. Time to go out, refresh, and have yourself some rest after a long, tiring week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first month of my new semester has passed. I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to study quite hard this semester, and everything seems overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have two homework this weekend, and both of them are from my coding classes. One is OOP, and the other one is the Programming Technique. Somehow I still haven&amp;rsquo;t finished both. It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating, especially when doubt starts to creep into your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many times have I wondered whether I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the right major to study or not? I&amp;rsquo;m not a bad student at school, and I can proudly say I belong to the top ones. I know my strength compared to other students and the admiration I get from people. I know all of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why do I still feel so empty every Sunday?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People said I should be proud and satisfied with everything I&amp;rsquo;ve got. They think that I&amp;rsquo;m confident, sociable, and extremely good at my major. I even have a better income than most of the students my age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only if they knew how much I have sacrificed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier, my two homework has caused me to doubt myself. It&amp;rsquo;s harmful to your mental health, especially when you&amp;rsquo;ve always tried so hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not intelligent. Not at all. Everything I&amp;rsquo;ve got was through trial and error. I hate when people say I&amp;rsquo;m smart, I&amp;rsquo;ll know how to resolve my own problem eventually. Or when they say I&amp;rsquo;m always confident and able to speak freely and get everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention. They don&amp;rsquo;t know my heart always beats like a drum while my body shakes every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I always have an unconfident feeling whenever I tackle a difficult problem or situation. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I&amp;rsquo;m reaching my limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s even worse when there&amp;rsquo;s no one there for you to share your thoughts. I have friends, and many of them can really lend me an ear, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard for them to understand me thoroughly. They don&amp;rsquo;t know this side of me, partly because I hardly show it, partly because we&amp;rsquo;re basically not in the same league. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying this to dignify myself, but when you&amp;rsquo;re better than people, you&amp;rsquo;ll always feel lonely because they won&amp;rsquo;t ever know how to become someone like you, to feel the way you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, it will be just me and myself. I wish there could be someone else here, but that&amp;rsquo;s the price I have to pay. Maybe one day I&amp;rsquo;ll be rewarded. One day&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, I still need to be strong. I might have a bad day like today, but I know I&amp;rsquo;ll come back stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get yourself up, as a new week is coming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A Letter To Myself</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A Letter To Myself" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You wake up. Sun is shining, birds are singing, got yourself a hot coffee and you look outside the window to watch the sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a wonderful start to the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, did you forget something? Today&amp;rsquo;s the final exam day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, you didn&amp;rsquo;t forget that. In fact, you knew it was coming, like, a month ago. Yeah, a month ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month ago, you got all your exam schedules. You had prepared and listed out everything you need to do to prepare for all those exams, so no big deal! Everything would be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks ago, your friend told you about a contest, which you found interesting. Or maybe you didn&amp;rsquo;t think it was that interesting, you just FOMO that you might lose the chance while everyone else didn&amp;rsquo;t. You spent a day just considering that, and in the end, you say no. But you lost a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, you were assigned a new task. It&amp;rsquo;s a new and challenging one since you&amp;rsquo;ve never worked on such projects before. At this time, you&amp;rsquo;ve finished some subjects&amp;rsquo; tests, and you had barely studied for the last one, the one that would come today. But still, that task was so intriguing, you decided to take that anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One week ago, you were still working on that project, at the same time studying for the final subject. You&amp;rsquo;re completely stressed out and exhausted. But more and more works kept on coming, just like Murphy&amp;rsquo;s law:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anything that can go wrong will go wrong.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You started to feel hopeless. Three days to the exam, you had only studied half the subject.&lt;br&gt;
Two days to the exam, still no progress. One day to the exam&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiktok, tiktok. Time still ticking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day to the exam. You felt hopeless. How come everything always has to come at once?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s not something new these days. I mean, we all have plenty of work to do. Some we can control. Some we can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, things still need to be done. It&amp;rsquo;s our responsibility to do that. We can&amp;rsquo;t control what&amp;rsquo;s coming to us, but we can control our emotions and act. How you face challenges, how you solve them, you&amp;rsquo;re the one who decides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to not be okay. But promise me, you&amp;rsquo;ll be strong afterward. Take a step back, like get some sleep, and return stronger than ever. Promise me you won&amp;rsquo;t give up, because you&amp;rsquo;ve tried so hard to go this far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better days will come, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
