<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Blog on The Real Hathai</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/categories/blog/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Blog on The Real Hathai</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hathai25.github.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A Letter To Myself</title>
        <link>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://hathai25.github.io/p/a-letter-to-myself/img.jpg" alt="Featured image of post A Letter To Myself" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;You wake up. Sun is shining, birds are singing, got yourself a hot coffee and you look outside the window to watch the sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a wonderful start to the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait, did you forget something? Today&amp;rsquo;s the final exam day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, you didn&amp;rsquo;t forget that. In fact, you knew it was coming, like, a month ago. Yeah, a month ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One month ago, you got all your exam schedules. You had prepared and listed out everything you need to do to prepare for all those exams, so no big deal! Everything would be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks ago, your friend told you about a contest, which you found interesting. Or maybe you didn&amp;rsquo;t think it was that interesting, you just FOMO that you might lose the chance while everyone else didn&amp;rsquo;t. You spent a day just considering that, and in the end, you say no. But you lost a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, you were assigned a new task. It&amp;rsquo;s a new and challenging one since you&amp;rsquo;ve never worked on such projects before. At this time, you&amp;rsquo;ve finished some subjects&amp;rsquo; tests, and you had barely studied for the last one, the one that would come today. But still, that task was so intriguing, you decided to take that anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One week ago, you were still working on that project, at the same time studying for the final subject. You&amp;rsquo;re completely stressed out and exhausted. But more and more works kept on coming, just like Murphy&amp;rsquo;s law:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anything that can go wrong will go wrong.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You started to feel hopeless. Three days to the exam, you had only studied half the subject.&lt;br&gt;
Two days to the exam, still no progress. One day to the exam&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiktok, tiktok. Time still ticking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day to the exam. You felt hopeless. How come everything always has to come at once?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s not something new these days. I mean, we all have plenty of work to do. Some we can control. Some we can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, things still need to be done. It&amp;rsquo;s our responsibility to do that. We can&amp;rsquo;t control what&amp;rsquo;s coming to us, but we can control our emotions and act. How you face challenges, how you solve them, you&amp;rsquo;re the one who decides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to not be okay. But promise me, you&amp;rsquo;ll be strong afterward. Take a step back, like get some sleep, and return stronger than ever. Promise me you won&amp;rsquo;t give up, because you&amp;rsquo;ve tried so hard to go this far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better days will come, I promise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
